here's one way to make sense of the
infinite sum of the powers of one-half
start with an isosceles triangle of Area
1 and cut it into two congruent
isosceles triangles shading one of them
so that we've shaded an area of a half
then repeat on the unshaded isosceles
triangle cutting it in half and shading
one so that we've shaded a quarter we
can continue this process indefinitely
each time we take the unshaded isosceles
triangle cut it in half and shade one
piece the area of this piece will be one
half the area of the previously shaded
triangle but as we do this infinitely we
end up with the Shaded region being the
sum of the powers of one-half on the
other hand as we do this forever we end
up filling the entire isosceles triangle
which has area one therefore the sum of
the powers of one-half is equal to one
foreign